Preliminary Inventory to the Joseph E. Persico Papers 1943-1980
Hoover Institution Archives
Joseph E. Persico papers,
1943-1980
81137
Hoover Institution Archives
5 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 1 envelope (2.9 linear feet)
Sound recordings and transcripts of interviews, correspondence, reports, drafts of writings, notes, printed matter, and photographs, relating to American secret service activities in Germany during World War II. Used as research material for the book by J. E. Persico, Piercing the Reich (1979). Includes photocopies of records of the U.S. Office of Strategic Services.
Persico, Joseph E.
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1981
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biography
American historian.
United States. Office of Strategic Services.; Germany--History--1933-1945.; Germany.; Phonotapes.; Secret service--United States.; United States--Armed Forces.; World War, 1939-1945--Germany.; World War, 1939-1945--Secret service.; World War, 1939-1945.
- Adrian (Box 1)
- Air operations
- Allen, Harper
- Ancrum, Calhoun
- Angleton, James
- Bancroft, Mary
- Bank, Aaron
- Boyd, Ann
- British intelligence
- Brittenham, Ray
- Bruce, David
- Burke, Michael
- Cannoot, Ferdinand
- Casualties
- Casey, William J.
- Central Intelligence Agency correspondence
- Chauffeur Mission
- Chisel Mission
- Copeland, Miles
- Correspondence, Miscellaneous
- Crocus Mission
- Dartmouth Mission
- Dawes/Houseboat Missions
- Deadwood Mission
- De Beaufort, Nam
- Dillon Mission
- Doctor Mission (Box 2)
- Downend Mission
- Dubuque Mission
- Dupont Mission
- European interviews - Correspondence
- Fleischer, Henry
- Geneva convention on prisoners of war
- Georgia/Virginia Missions
- Gestapo
- Goldberg, Arthur
- Gould, Joseph
- Greenup Mission
- Grell, William (Box 3)
- Grimm, Kurt
- Haass, Walter
- Hadey, Gilbert
- Hammer Mission
- Helms, Richard
- Hoguet, Peter
- Homespun Mission
- Hood, Cornelia
- Houston, Lawrence
- Hyde, Henry
- Hymoff, Ed
- Interviewees - Correspondence
- Interviews - Lists
- Issikides, Barbara
- Italian-based missions
- Joan/Eleanor Missions
- Jolis, Albert
- Juchniewicz, Bill
- Jungk, Robert
- Karlow, Peter
- Katz, Milton
- Kirstein, Wilhelm
- Kolbe, Fritz
- Kurz, Edmund
- Laverge, Jan
- Lemberger, Martha
- Lowenstein, Dyno
- Luxe Mission
- McCulloch, John
- Mallet Mission
- Mero, Peter
- Meucke, Carl
- Miller, Gerald
- Mimi Mission
- Molden, Fritz
- Morgan, Henry
- Oakes, John
- Office of Strategic Services (Box 4)
  - History
  - Organization charts
  - Telephone directory
- Operations - Lists
- Painter Mission
- Peenemuende
- Perry, Hart
- Photographs - Correspondence and lists
- Pitt Mission
- Pratt, George
- Prester, Julio
- Questions for interviewees
- Reddick, W. C.
- Roman, Howard
- Roosevelt, Kermit
- Rubens Mission (Albert Pauley)
- Sichel, Peter
- Simpson, Stephen
- Steiner, Herbert
- Strahle, Carl
- Summary of book for publisher
- Sutton, Henry
- Swiss operations
- Teper, Lazare
- Thalberg, Hans
- Thompson, Robert E. S.
- Titles for book
- Tofte, Hans
- Training agents
- Troy Mission
- Turano, Anthony
- Turnbull, William
- Ulmer, Alfred C.
- Ulsamer, Edgar
- Van Arkel, Gerhard
- Van Dyck, Orpha
- Viertel, Peter
- Vujnovich, George
- War diary (Box 5)
- Watt, Richard
- Wynberg, Hans
- Youri Mission
- Ancrum, Calhoun (Box 6, Tape 1)
- Baker, Mary (Tape 2)
- Boyd, Ann (Tape 3)
- Brittenham, Raymond (Tape 4)
- Bruce, David (Tape 5)
- Burke, Michael, and Robert Thompson (Tape 6)
- Cannoot, Ferdinand, and Kurt Grimm (Tape 7)
- Casey, William J. (Tape 8-9)
- Copeland, Miles (Tape 10)
  General note
  Use copy reference number: 81137_a_0007743
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes various music recordings
- De Beaufort, Nam, and Anthony Turano (Tape 11)
- Fleischer, Henry (Tape 12)
- Goldberg, Arthur (Tape 13)
- Gould, Joseph (Tape 14-15)
- Legradi, Helene, and Robert Jungk (Tape 16)
- Grell, William (Tape 17)
- Gruber, Karl, and Wilhelm Kirstein (Tape 18)
- Haass, Walter (sound recording of interview), 22 June 1977 (Tape 19)
  Use copy reference number: 81137_a_0005884
- Hoguet, Peter (Tape 20)
- Hood, Cordelia (Tape 21)
- Houston, Lawrence (Tape 22)
- Hyde, Henry (Tape 23)
- Hyde, Henry, and Peter Sichel (Tape 24)
- Jolis, Albert (Tape 25-27)
- Karlow, Peter (Tape 28)
- Katz, Milton (Tape 29)
- Kirstein, Wilhelm (Tape 30)
- Kurz, Edmund (Tape 31)
- Lowenstein, Dyno (sound recording of interviews), 29 October 1976 11 November 1976 (Tape 32-33)
  Use copy reference number: 81137_a_0005886 and 81137_a_0005887
- Mayer, Frederick (sound recording of interview), 5 July 1977 (Tape 34)
  Use copy reference number: 81137_a_0005627
- Miller, Gerald (Tape 35)
- Molden, Fritz (Tape 36)
- Muecke, Carl (Tape 37)
- Oakes, John (Tape 38)
- Pauley, Albert (Tape 39)
- Perry, Hart, and Kermit Roosevelt (Tape 40)
- Pratt, George (Tape 41)
- Primbs, Max (sound recording of interview), 1 October 1977 (Tape 42)
  Use copy reference number: 81137_a_0005891
- Reddick, Willis (Tape 43)
- Roman, Howard (Tape 44)
- Sichel, Peter (Box 7, Tape 45)
- Strahle, Carl (Tape 46)
- Sutton, Henry (Tape 47)
- Teper, Lazare (Tape 48-49)
- Thompson, Robert E. S. (Tape 50)
- Tofte, Hans (Tape 51-52)
- Turano, Anthony (Tape 53)
- Turnbull, William (Tape 54)
- Ulmer, Alfred (sound recording of interview), 23 April 1977 (Tape 55-56)
  Use copy reference number: 81137_a_0005628
- Ulsamer, Edgar (Tape 57-58)
- Van Arkel, Gerhard (Tape 59-61)
- Van Dyck, Orpha (Tape 62)
- Viertel, Peter, and Fritz Molden (Tape 63)
- Vujnovich, George (Tape 64)
- Weber, Franz (sound recording of interview), October 1977 (Tape 65)
  Cassette label has the date as 1 Oct; date given at the top of the Tape is 2 Oct. Use copy reference number: 81137_a_0005634
- Wolf, David (Tape 66)